<Database>
	<GameDBStringTable ID="LOC_EN_ADDON_OTOR_DIAGNOSES">
	<LanguageCode>en</LanguageCode>
	<LanguageNameLocalized>English</LanguageNameLocalized>
	<Contributors>
	<Name>James Buckham</Name>
	</Contributors>
	<LocalizedStrings>
		<!-- Diagnoses -->
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_CSP</LocID>                         
		<Text>Chronic Sinusitis (With Polyps)</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_CSP_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Chronic Sinusitis is a condition where the sinus becomes inflammed for more than 3 months.Cases can be caused by allergies and etc.).Treatment for this is surgery to remove the polyps and a course of saline nasal spray. </Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_SPT</LocID>                         
		<Text>Strep Throat</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_SPT_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Strep throat is an infection caused by a type of bacteria (group A streptococcus). Strep bacteria cause almost a third of all sore throats. Strep throat usually needs treatment with antibiotics. </Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_HFM</LocID>                         
		<Text>Hand Foot Mouth Disease</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_HFM_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) is a common infection caused by a group of viruses. It typically begins with a fever and feeling generally unwell. This is followed a day or two later by flat discolored spots or bumps that may blister, on the hands, feet and mouth. There is no treatment for this disease, you only have to treat the symptoms until the disease is over. </Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_CSN</LocID>                         
		<Text>Chronic Sinusitis</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_CSN_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Chronic Sinusitis is a condition where the sinus becomes inflammed for more than 3 months.Cases can be caused by allergies and etc.).Treatment for this is a course of saline nasal spray. </Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_ASN</LocID>                         
		<Text>Allergic Sinusitis</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_ASN_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Sinusitis is a condition where the sinus becomes inflammed.Cases can be caused by allergies and etc.). In this case it is caused by allergies and treatment for this is antihistamines. </Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_ENS</LocID>                         
		<Text>Empty Nose Syndrome</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_ENS_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Empty nose syndrome (ENS), one form of secondary atrophic rhinitis, is a clinical syndrome in which people who have clear nasal passages experience a range of symptoms, most commonly feelings of nasal obstruction, nasal dryness and crusting, and a sensation of being unable to breathe. </Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_MED</LocID>                         
		<Text>Meniere's Disease (Mild)</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_MED_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Meniere's disease is a disorder of the inner ear that can lead to dizzy spells (vertigo) and hearing loss. In most cases, Meniere's disease affects only one ear.Meniere's disease can occur at any age, but it usually starts between young and middle-aged adulthood. It's considered a chronic condition, but various treatments can help relieve symptoms and minimize the long-term impact on your life. </Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_SED</LocID>                         
		<Text>Meniere's Disease (Severe)</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_SED_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Meniere's disease is a disorder of the inner ear that can lead to dizzy spells (vertigo) and hearing loss. In most cases, Meniere's disease affects only one ear.Meniere's disease can occur at any age, but it usually starts between young and middle-aged adulthood. It's considered a chronic condition, but various treatments can help relieve symptoms and minimize the long-term impact on your life. </Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_GRD</LocID>                         
		<Text>Gastroesophageal reflux disease</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_GRD_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Gastroesophageal reflux disease, or GERD, is a digestive disorder that affects the lower esophageal sphincter (LES), the ring of muscle between the esophagus and stomach. Many people, including pregnant women, suffer from heartburn or acid indigestion caused by GERD. If left untreated it will cause esophagitis, Barett's esophagus and even esophageal cancer.</Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_OSA</LocID>                         
		<Text>Obstructive Sleep Apnea</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_OSA_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) is the most common type of sleep apnea and is characterised by repeated episodes of complete or partial obstructions of the upper airway during sleep, despite the effort to breathe, and is usually associated with a reduction in blood oxygen saturation.</Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_MEDR</LocID>                         
		<Text>Rupture of the eardrum</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_MEDR_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>A ruptured eardrum (tympanic membrane perforation) is a hole or tear in the thin tissue that separates your ear canal from your middle ear (eardrum).A ruptured eardrum can result in hearing loss. It can also make your middle ear vulnerable to infections.A ruptured eardrum usually heals within a few weeks without treatment. But sometimes it requires a patch or surgical repair to heal.</Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_SEDR</LocID>                         
		<Text>Unhealed Rupture of the eardrum</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_SEDR_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>A ruptured eardrum (tympanic membrane perforation) is a hole or tear in the thin tissue that separates your ear canal from your middle ear (eardrum).A ruptured eardrum can result in hearing loss. It can also make your middle ear vulnerable to infections.A ruptured eardrum usually heals within a few weeks without treatment. But sometimes it requires a patch or surgical repair to heal.</Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_NAR</LocID>                         
		<Text>Non-allergic Rhinitis</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_NAR_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Nonallergic rhinitis involves chronic sneezing or a congested, drippy nose with no apparent cause. The symptoms of nonallergic rhinitis are similar to those of hay fever (allergic rhinitis), but none of the usual evidence of an allergic reaction is present.Nonallergic rhinitis can affect children and adults, but it's more common after age 20. Triggers of nonallergic rhinitis symptoms vary and can include certain odors or irritants in the air, changes in the weather, some medications, certain foods, and chronic health conditions.A diagnosis of nonallergic rhinitis is made after an allergic cause is ruled out. This may require allergy skin or blood tests.</Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>TRM_JM_LYC</LocID>                         
		<Text>Blunt Laryngeal Trauma</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>TRM_JM_LYC_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Laryngeal trauma is injury to the voice box, or larynx, the upper portion of the airway where the vocal cords are located.Blunt trauma to the airway is rather common, but happens less frequently in children than in adults. In pediatric cases, the trauma is usually caused by a fall or blow to the neck, or other throat injury.The damage can range from minor vocal cord weakness to fractures of the cartilage structures of the larynx or trachea. These fractures can cause air to escape into the neck and chest, leading to significant respiratory compromise and even death if not diagnosed and treated quickly.In childhood, the larynx and trachea have a soft cartilage structure and small size. Therefore, pediatric fractures occur less often. Even the largest hospitals only see a small number of real laryngotracheal fracture cases.</Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>TRM_JM_LYL</LocID>                         
		<Text>Laryngeal Trauma</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>TRM_JM_LYL_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Laryngeal trauma is injury to the voice box, or larynx, the upper portion of the airway where the vocal cords are located.Blunt trauma to the airway is rather common, but happens less frequently in children than in adults. In pediatric cases, the trauma is usually caused by a fall or blow to the neck, or other throat injury.The damage can range from minor vocal cord weakness to fractures of the cartilage structures of the larynx or trachea. These fractures can cause air to escape into the neck and chest, leading to significant respiratory compromise and even death if not diagnosed and treated quickly.In childhood, the larynx and trachea have a soft cartilage structure and small size. Therefore, pediatric fractures occur less often. Even the largest hospitals only see a small number of real laryngotracheal fracture cases</Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_CLA</LocID>                         
		<Text>Cholesteatoma</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_CLA_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Cholesteatoma is a destructive and expanding growth consisting of keratinizing squamous epithelium in the middle ear and/or mastoid process. Cholesteatomas are not cancerous as the name may suggest, but can cause significant problems because of their erosive and expansile properties. This can result in the destruction of the bones of the middle ear (ossicles), as well as growth through the base of the skull into the brain. They often become infected and can result in chronically draining ears. Treatment almost always consists of surgical removal.</Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_LGP</LocID>                         
		<Text>Laryngeal papillomatosis</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_LGP_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Laryngeal papillomatosis, also known as recurrent respiratory papillomatosis or glottal papillomatosis, is a rare medical condition in which benign tumors (papilloma) form along the aerodigestive tract. There are two variants based on the age of onset: juvenile and adult laryngeal papillomatosis. The tumors are caused by human papillomavirus (HPV) infection of the throat. The tumors may lead to narrowing of the airway, which may cause vocal changes or airway obstruction. Laryngeal papillomatosis is initially diagnosed through indirect laryngoscopy upon observation of growths on the larynx and can be confirmed through a biopsy. Treatment for laryngeal papillomatosis aims to remove the papillomas and limit their recurrence. Due to the recurrent nature of the virus, repeated treatments usually are needed. Laryngeal papillomatosis is primarily treated surgically, though supplemental nonsurgical and/or medical treatments may be considered in some cases. The evolution of laryngeal papillomatosis is highly variable. Though total recovery may be observed, it is often persistent despite treatment. The number of new cases of laryngeal papillomatosis cases is at approximately 4.3 cases per 100,000 children and 1.8 cases per 100,000 adults annually.</Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_VCN</LocID>                         
		<Text>Vocal Cord Nodules</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_VCN_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Vocal nodules are hard, rough, noncancerous growths on your vocal cords. They can be as small as a pinhead or as large as a pea. You get nodules from straining or overusing your voice, especially from singing, yelling, or talking loudly or for a long period of time. Vocal nodules go by other names based on their cause.</Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_APX</LocID>                         
		<Text>Anaphylaxis</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
        <GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_APX_DESCRIPTION</LocID>             
		<Text>Anaphylaxis is a severe, potentially life-threatening allergic reaction. It can occur within seconds or minutes of exposure to something you're allergic to, such as peanuts or bee stings.Anaphylaxis causes your immune system to release a flood of chemicals that can cause you to go into shock — your blood pressure drops suddenly and your airways narrow, blocking breathing. Signs and symptoms include a rapid, weak pulse; a skin rash; and nausea and vomiting. Common triggers include certain foods, some medications, insect venom and latex.Anaphylaxis requires an injection of epinephrine and a follow-up trip to an emergency room. If you don't have epinephrine, you need to go to an emergency room immediately. If anaphylaxis isn't treated right away, it can be fatal.</Text>  
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_SWE</LocID>                         
		<Text>Severe Otitis Externa</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		
		<GameDBLocalizedString>      
		<LocID>DIA_JM_GEE</LocID>                         
		<Text>Severe Glue Ear</Text>	
		</GameDBLocalizedString>
		

		
		 
	</LocalizedStrings>
	</GameDBStringTable>
</Database>

